<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Josiah McKay</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Josiah McKay</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Docker Migration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/docker-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/docker-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the second in a series of articles detailing my 2024 homelab update.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said in my last post, my homelab has consisted of an application and storage server, with the application server being a 2013 iMac running Ubuntu Server 20.04 LTS. This has worked out fine, but I am running up against the 8GB RAM limit of the iMac, especially now that I have deployed Immich as photo storage. I also wanted to run more than just containers (Local DNS, Home Assistant, Kubernetes) so I wanted a hypervisor OS to be able to easily manage all of that. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard a lot about Proxmox, and since it is basically just Debian plus QEMU I figured it would be a nice easy choice. Plus, it&amp;rsquo;s free and open source!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TrueNAS Migration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/truenas-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/truenas-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally posted on a Wordpress blog that I had and forgot about. It is being posted here for completeness of my homelab journey. It was originally posted in the summer of 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first in a series of articles detailing my 2024 homelab update.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been running my current homelab off an old 2013 or 2015 iMac I got from my grandfather, as well as a repurposed gaming PC I built in 2020. The iMac has been my application server (using Docker and Docker Compose to manage the applications), and the gaming PC has been my storage server, running TrueNAS CORE, which you may know is FreeBSD based. Nothing wrong with FreeBSD per se, but I am rather partial to Debian, so when I saw that TrueNAS SCALE was Debian-based, I knew I wanted to switch. Additionally, the 8GB of the iMac was starting to be a limiting factor, and I also wanted to do things “more correctly” like using a hypervisor, Kubernetes, and more Infrastructure-as-Code (IaC).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Homelab</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-homelab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally posted on a Wordpress blog that I had and forgot about. It is being posted here for completeness of my homelab journey. It was originally posted in early 2023.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to layout what my homelab looks like now because this summer I hope to change some things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;storage&#34;&gt;Storage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current storage server is one that started life as a gaming computer that I built back in 2020. I had gotten a wild itch to build a computer (my first ever build), that admittedly I didn’t really plan much out. I also didn’t really factor in the fact that I am not a gamer. So after I built it I toyed around with Cities:Skylines, Stardew Valley, and other such games, but the computer largely sat unused (or at least under-used).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my site! Here I will be talking about the things that interest me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purposes of this site are three-fold:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information archive for myself.&lt;/strong&gt; I like to homelab and selfhost, and sometimes I forget the things that I have done, or how I did them. Ths site will be a reposatory of all my adventures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information archive for others.&lt;/strong&gt; The internet is a tremendous invention, allowing the dispursal of information accross the globe nearly instantaniously. I hope that at least some of these posts will be helpful to someone in some way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evidence for future employers&lt;/strong&gt;: A resume can only say so much. I hope that this website serves as proof of what I can do to anyone who hapens to be looking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the writing, this site is still very new and I am still learning all the options for &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adityatelange/hugo-PaperMod&#34;&gt;PaperMod&lt;/a&gt; (the framework and theme, respectively, that this blog runs off of).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-am-a-christian&#34;&gt;I am a Christian&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in the God of the Bible. My believes are consistent with the Westminster Confession of Faith&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-am--a-technology-professional&#34;&gt;I am  a technology professional&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am particularly interested in backend infrastructure &amp;ndash; think server management, configuration management, networking, that sort of stuff. I am continually amazed at the trumendous things that computers are able to do, and I want to be a part of making all of that possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/resume/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;education--certification&#34;&gt;Education &amp;amp; Certification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Millersville University&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bachelor of Arts in Entertainment Technology [2021]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minor: Music; General Applied Engineering and Technology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community College of the Air Force&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Associates in Applied Engineering [2020]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;certificates&#34;&gt;Certificates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CompTIA A+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CompTIA Network+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CompTIA Security+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;professional-experience&#34;&gt;Professional Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-support-technician&#34;&gt;Technology Support Technician&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;University of South Carolina; College of Arts and Sciences&lt;/strong&gt; [February  2023 – Present]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Took over primary desktop support for Mathematics and Statistics departments
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created inventory and provided continuation of support for over 150 desktop and laptop computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitated Windows 11 migration for over 60 unsupported computers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created and maintained documentation for unique departmental needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead the transition of support from email to ServiceNow, decreasing support wait time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Administered existing VMs and physical servers
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisted in transitioning three legacy servers to the University’s VMware environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated existing VM to current security standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintained Active Directory computer and user group records for Mathematics and Statistics departments and modified them as appropriate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolved over 150 Desktop Support incidents
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tier 1 Network Issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;user-support-technician&#34;&gt;User Support Technician&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;University of South Carolina; College of Arts and Sciences&lt;/strong&gt; [July 2021 – February 2023]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
